

Priyank Gupta

Software Engineer

Contact

Address

Bangalore, India 560100

Phone

+918588996479

E-mail

priyankg101@gmail.com

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com /in/priyank-gupta-02475b4b

WWW

https://priyankg101.github.io/priyankme/

Technical Profile

- React.js
- JavaScript
- Next.js
- TypeScript
- HTML
- CSS
- Bootstrap
- Gatsby
- jQuery
- MongoDB
- PostgreSQL
- Node.js

Software Engineer with 2 years of experience in Java, seeking to transition into React and related frameworks. Experienced with front-end technologies and RESTful APIs, with a strong understanding of the software development life cycle and a track record of delivering quality code. Committed to staying up-to-date with the latest trends in web development and constantly learning. In free time, enjoys building personal projects to further develop skills and creativity. Brings technical skills, attention to detail, and a passion for clean and efficient code to any organization.

Work History

2021-07 -Current

Associate Software Engineer

Amdocs, Pune, MH

- Developed and deployed Spring Boot application on Microsoft Azure as PaaS utilizing REST APIs for efficient data exchange resulting in 40% reduction in response time.
- Implemented Continuous Integration pipelines using Azure DevOps, ensuring seamless integration and deployment of code changes with 99% success rate.
- Resolved live production errors timely and effectively, ensuring smooth functioning of mission-critical applications with average resolution time of 2 hours.
- Maintained ColdFusion application hosted on Microsoft Azure as laaS, ensuring high availability and optimal performance with uptime of 99.95%.
- Collaborated with business analysts to deliver high-availability solutions for mission-critical applications ensuring their reliable and consistent operation resulting in 20% increase in customer satisfaction.
- Analyzed configuration files and logs to identify and resolve root causes of problems, improving overall stability and performance of applications reducing downtime by 50%.
- Installed system updates to address vulnerabilities and reduce security risks, ensuring safety and protection of sensitive information with 100% compliance to industry standards.

2021-01 - Cloud Engineering Intern

Microsoft Azure

Competencies

Development Lifecycles

Testing and maintenance

Algorithm implementation

Project budgeting

Software Documentation

2021-06 Deloitte India, Bengaluru, KA

 Engaged in Cloud Adoption projects, working with stakeholders to plan, design, and implement cloud-based solutions.

Demonstrated ability to develop innovative and effective solutions to complex problems, resulting in improved efficiency and productivity.

Designed and developed a user-friendly chat-bot frontend using Flutter, providing customers with seamless and interactive experience.

Education

2017-01 - B.Tech: Electronics and Communication Engineering

Vellore Institute of Technology - Vellore, TN

GPA: 8.49

2016-04 - Intermediate Science

2017-03 St Teresa School - Ghaziabad, UP

Score: 88.8%

2014-04 - High School Diploma

2015-03 St Teresa School - Ghaziabad, UP

CGPA: 10

Certifications

AZ-900 Certified by Microsoft Azure

Complete React Developer [2022] - by ZTM on Udemy